well it's it's lovely to talk again
because it's been far too long and since
we have like I think we parted last time
in London when we had a meal together
with your wife and when I was there for
the lush spring price and right that's
the last time I saw you the last time we
talked though was about I think some
potential project in Alberta or you were
yeah of course yeah that's it's
interesting I I'm still in touch with
the person who contacted me but they
lost their bid for the Calgary I think
it Olympics again or some other Olympics
I can't remember exactly but basically
it's one of those leads that didn't go
anywhere right oh yeah
the real part of them they circle back
though they like what I would love to
get your perspective on this is this how
do we because you just said that my
works contributed in a small way to more
and more people being interested in
regeneration and regenerative practice
and lots of people use this to him and I
personally feel like having having done
the regenerative practitioner training I
should have realized how deep of a
practice there was behind working in
this way that I wasn't even aware when I
wrote my book and yeah we knew that but
you do you figure that out at some point
and and and at the time by the way by
the way Daniel it keeps getting deeper
yeah you never this that's what's
powerful about this work is that you
can't possibly know it it's a continual
journey of evolution yeah for me that
that's the interesting bit personally
because on the one hand I feel like I've
been approaching the same like drinking
on from some of the same wells and
approaching the same way of working and
and and so some of the things I feel
like I've already heard in in other
context other pathways from other
mentors having worked with John Todd and
David oh and um but then there's there's
something very specific that in terms of
the frameworks in in regenerative
practices practice that really
invite people to reframe the way they
they think and I'm and and so I now find
myself like on the one hand the way I
simplify it and in my mind is that Carol
holds a really sort of true to the
gospel kind of very close to her chest
type version yeah
reach out that's true and then in a way
Regenesis group Andrew Genesis into the
Institute who always acknowledged the
depth of drawing from Carol's work but
also through all the other people in the
group having developed this are already
to some extent the next roll out from
that kind of making it more easily
digestible to more people and actively
yes that's intentional yeah and and and
and to some extent I feel like I'm I'm
the next spring out of almost sort of
pointing at Regenesis group and saying
here you can this is where you can go a
lot deeper if if you resonate strongly
with this call to undo the damage that
we've done for far too long
and but I I now see a sense that that
business and like large corporations and
everybody is jumping in on this like the
last round about this time last year
before last in December 2018 when a
Walter Thompson put out this report on
regeneration as the new sustainability
or whatever that that was a kind of
clear signal that something was shifting
and now like I was recently in London
invited to speak to people who are
business consultants and business
leaders around how regenerative
economics and mainstream business could
somehow connect and I how do you sense
like how do we work with this huge
amount of interest that now exists and
the fact that there are lots of
consultants
just basically going through their web
page ins crossing out sustainable and
it's true oh my goodness it's happening
it's a terrible thing but how do you how
do you meet that like how do you meet
the demand how do how do you how do you
stay true to the depth of a different
type of practice that starts from
personal development and ultimately
shifting consciousness yeah what you
said yes just what you said there is so
key Daniel it starts from personal
development actually it starts from a
whole because you can start anywhere you
can start when I first started it would
for me the real rep if I can speak about
myself for a second the real revelation
was oh my gosh this is a whole system
and I don't mean the holes you know
you've heard me kind of be snarky about
it it's taking it's not taking the SDGs
and putting them in a circle and calling
it a hole that's not a hole hmm
it's or lead points and putting it in a
circle it's still a list in a circle and
that's okay but what is really working
with a hole mean and I think the
principles that I think what we need to
get out there are the principles and
because I think if we the way Carol's
characterize it I characterizing them
five character Carol characterizes them
in seven doesn't matter as long as you
have those core principles they're to
get people to think about because you
have to hold all seven together or I
prefer five actually wholeness essence
reciprocity potential not problems
developmental and missing that's fine I
know that's five I combined I was gonna
throw it throw nodal in there and
knodel's the one that I would actually
get rid of because I don't think that's
essential
Carol calls it as a Carol thing it's
essential for change but it's not
essential for the way a living system
works is my opinion we should actually
talk about that let me say wholeness
essence potential developmental
reciprocity or field building knodel and
I'm missing one anyway yeah sir does
well maybe speak to if you could speak
to each one of them briefly then that
the seventh one will pop back as you do
that there I can I'll just pop into this
for a second
nice picture what do you look at that a
picture of you and at a conference or
something
Oh nested this for me that's so key that
for me scale linking the scale linking
understanding of participation and
wholeness was something that I felt was
why I resonated so strongly with a lot
of the Regenesis work because that sort
of I came in more from a complexity
angle and yeah and a life science like
being a biologist and that that nested
Ness is it strike it's gigantic cuz she
because and and the parent so also I
would add another one to this just
because I for me its meaningful when you
find you're working with paradox you
know you're on the right track so the
paradox of nested miss is as Bucky
fuller said you know we've got to draw a
boundary and then you erase it because
it's a figment of your imagination so
you're continually iterating with this
living right almost so that getting back
to personal development you can start
with a hole and the hole asks you will
know how do we work with the hole once
we understand that essence right and
because that's key is essence in essence
is so key and from the Western mind
anyway so how do you work with that
well it means I've got to be actually
have a group actualization skills I have
to actually have group development
skills integration skills right to be
able do that in order for me to be
effective as a group if I'm a jerk it's
not going to work very well yeah so so
all those it's just so beautiful
that you you cannot do this without
personal
and the gigantic problem that I have in
my work my particular consulting was
Daniel is that people they hear the word
regeneration I think this might speak to
some of your concerns because it's still
a concern of mine is that people say
well oh this regeneration sounds great
you know they want to they're
well-meaning right they want to do
sustainability at the best level they
can they want to leave a legacy behind
because they've screwed up things in the
past or they believe in systems or
something so they hire us but it's
they're hiring us to deliver a project
hmm and that's an outcome of the process
it is not the reason for the process but
it's not the nature of the process the
process is about our evolution and and
how we evolve with that splice that
we're building this project in and how
that place and system informs the
project and in order to do that we have
to change our attitude who we who we are
in order to work with a community in a
different way and work with the
ecosystem in a different way in order to
inform that project well that personal
development angle when you realize that
the fractal of what of who I am will
help realize what the earth is to become
is gigantic because if we don't leave
people with that then it's not going to
stay it's not gonna stick and that is
the hard part in our in my particular
work through consulting is there's a
position as a point within a month or
two months of getting a project where
the client says and I this is a quote
from one quiet one client my minister
doesn't get away with saying the shit
you say bill you're fired
Wow okay mm-hmm
so I've had that happen quite a few
times what's also interesting Daniel and
if you've heard me say this before
virtually every one of those clients
except for one have hired us back within
a year engines that's powerful
yeah the it but it takes them a year to
process that stuff and they say oh they
were on you know cuz they're reflecting
right they realize gee I fired this guy
he was a good
but he was a jerk - you know he's trying
to tell was working fast and that wasn't
exactly api's he didn't calabash noble
impact in X amount of time yeah well but
of course it all goes hand at hand the
KPI should can be there the whole the
whole mechanics function needs to be
there but it needs to be accompanied by
being and will mm-hmm so you know this
is where Auto Sharma's work - it's very
similar you know uses Rudolf Steiners
hand heart in mind at those three
dimensions of existence from the Greeks
are really what are the derivation of
our work and all this kind of charisma
out there that needs to happen so it's
very difficult from a functional world
and especially in the United States
which is why the United States is our
least successful country in terms of
clientele they only see that world
through function and they only see the
world look function and that being and
we'll dimension is almost alien to them
hmm so how do we introduce this in such
a way that they realize this they're
stepping into a whole different journey
[Music]
that's the big the big one and how like
for me and I'm saying this with lots of
love towards the work and the passion
for getting it out there in its depth
and is the for me is the there in some
of the language used initially seems to
ask people to almost induct themselves
into a certain kind of cult
well cult or a kind of in-group and that
way you sort of wonder for example the
word essence if you like if you define
what essence means to you how would you
bring somebody if somebody says you talk
about essence a lot and what do you mean
by that the poor the the
the you the unique attribute of a living
entity at the core the core unique
attribute of living entity who makes
what makes Daniel Daniel and then I'll
always tell stories that my wife did not
fall in love with me because I have road
rage which I do have a little but she
fell in love with me after all that
personality bullshit there's a core that
she fell in love with right mmm-hmm
that's essence that's a good way so our
personality is not essence people
confuse that a lot personality are is a
psychosis right based on how we even
brought up or how we react to things
personality is necessary but the rest of
our lives basically by the time were
five or six years old we and I think we
know this intuitively we put kids into a
you know governmental education program
and it beats or social systems beat what
the genius that is in every individual
is just is buried so that you can fit in
and it isn't until you're 30 or 40 years
old that you start really discovering
rediscovering you know you'd say I used
to love that or this is what I used to
do but my father didn't let me do it
right or something and realize well that
was bad on him and bad on me it's time
to rebirth that yeah and I think that's
the amount of self limiting beliefs that
we carry from childhood is phenomenal I
still have them yeah Tim you I think we
all do it I think that's part of the
personal development journey is to
really it's it's one step to become
aware of them takes another 10 years to
actually do something and that's what
makes this work so powerful yeah because
you're rebirthing yeah so it's not
regenerating out there it's regenerating
at all those nested levels right this is
really interesting because that's
another thing that I increasingly get to
and when when people ask me about what's
different
and for me in the notion of regeneration
is also an invitation to meet breakdown
collapse and the the dissolution of
patterns that no longer serve em death
something that loses its sting because
you really understand the nested
wholeness of life being fundamentally
interconnected and really just one
process and all boundaries including the
one of scale truth ego just yeah
Carterville I am you and you are me yeah
you that's this is the journey and so
this is why this practice is is unlearn
herbal right I mean because it's
learning it's a continual evolution of
discovery of self and what any universe
mmm-hmm yeah I know I was reminded in
terms of historian with one of the
clients and it's whether we got to the
Commonwealth project that Ben is doing
such wonderful work still offering his
services to I know Dan's been yeah
commit something happens coming out of
that well I really found I he explained
to me how he sees it and since then I
see it very differently would well
because he at the last meeting again I
was sort of looking at what had actually
moved and whether the these the
potential that we all saw in the
beginning of somehow affecting the way
that development is done in 53 nations
around the world I'm touching 2.4
billion people at all it's all very ah
what a great opportunity but um been
said to me for him the most important
and confirmed outcome of it all is the
learning that Freya Yost has done in the
process of him mentoring her to run the
the project and and that's wonderful
because that also speaks to the levels
of work because ultimately that is she
already did such wonderful work before
she started with corpus from
and started to work on common earth and
and now to have deepened under Ben's
mentor egde into this way of working
it's guaranteed that for the rest of her
life she will do amazing stuff and and
and that might say that's that's the
deliverable yeah
the deliverable is capability mmm
capacity and capability and you know
before my class from the school what's
interesting capacity and capability and
the answer is I asked them I said did
you have the capacity to understand what
I was talking about before we started
this course well they had the capacity
but I couldn't know they didn't
understand Natalie now you have now that
you had the capacity you have the
capability to evolve mm-hmm something
along those lines so when we leave the
deliverable for a regenerative project
is building the capacity and capability
of people to co-evolved period that's it
with Nate that's exactly right with each
other that's that's why I stopped just
co-evolve as coevolution requires the
whole us care person-to-person person
the group person the nature because
that's the other bit with regard to
essence like am i right in seeing that
what what I call bio cultural uniqueness
of place is very similar to essence of
place like it's just it's both the
specific uniqueness of that ecosystem
and its history but also the culture and
the potential that is held in gel
absolutely leading up to a possibility
of transformation and and whether that's
realized or not yeah i mean i think i
think biocultural is a fine term i think
though it typically gets Bane alized I'm
hold on I'm just gonna make it across
this intersection here before Mike turns
okay perfect so in the context of
because you made mention earlier in our
conversation you mentioned climate
change
late last year seems to have been a year
where so many people have woken up to a
new urgency around climate change to the
point that not enough people that we're
doing that almost we're living the
shortcoming of allopathic medicine and
we're we're all like fighting as if it's
a cancer or whatever you want to call it
and we're fighting this this anathema of
climate change using all these bellicose
language and all that um but we're not
really asking what's the cause of the
symptom that's exactly right is climate
change exactly that's what I tell people
I say the same thing Daniel I say
climate change is a symptom mm-hmm it's
not the issue and the issue is our
disconnection the issue is our
fragmentation of the world and even
treating climate change is a problem it
is not gonna is not going to work
exactly because we saw him climb solve
climate change let's say cold fusion to
somehow and realize tomorrow we're still
destroying the planet ma'am for me for
me that was always I mean good thing is
with cold fusion that it's been 40 years
away for for more than 40 years and it's
still 40 years away store and um but but
I always felt and I remember this like
when I was in a Center for alternative
technology in the early 2000s and we
always talked about how even if we
discovered one of those Magic Bullet
technologies and we probably then for
sure destroy the planet because we
haven't done the deeper work of
understanding
the misguided Ness that has come from
our sense of separation from each other
and from from from the living world like
that the lack of understanding that that
everything personal is planetary and
everything planetary is personal and
that we that we now need to re-envision
ourselves as part of life as a planetary
process yeah but when we understand this
but then if you look at the news in the
evening or even just walk down your
neighborhood and see interactions
between people and so on are you still
hopeful that we can can make this shift
with the urges of climate you know I'm
not I'm not anymore I used to be but but
the just just my wheel your phone
balances I was had a party on New Year's
Eve and there were a number of
climate-related communal experts there
and we're in Cambridge Mass right
there's lots of people doing this and
and actually it was really kind of an
interesting attitude this one guy Bruce
his name a few books anyway he just said
well it's over we lost and you know what
he was actually his attitude was
actually really positive he said lost
and then I didn't get into into a death
with him but you know how do we prepare
his question was how do we prepare for
those that will survive yeah I mean this
is this is I hear this over and over
again like the the guy Michael McDonald
that words within and enroller and and
friends in the common earth project he's
a medical doctor who set up the the
global resilience Network and he's been
for 40 years of his career he's been in
every sort of major outbreak of Ebola or
hantavirus or you name it if somewhere
in the world due to natural catastrophe
of war or something there's the danger
of having an epidemic breakout he'll be
in the in the first response team and
and he he shared with me that when he
was a young man and then in the late or
mid 1980s he was part of a UK US
government sponsored project that pretty
much concluded in a report through the
White House that if we wouldn't
fundamentally change our way of doing
things by the mid-1990s then by the 2030
is somewhere between 2030 and 2050 four
to five billion people on planet earth
and everything that if you look at the
hard science they were right back then
we haven't changed anything since then
oh and we're pretty much on course for
something as traumatic as that and well
look at outlook at Australia yeah
California but how do we go on like that
from weapons that's the question and I'm
working on that and believe me I'm
spending a lot of time thinking about
that and not maybe not effectively but
I've actually put a couple lets talk
because I put a couple things in motion
just this week one is so I'm part of a
interesting I also feel we need to get
out of the talking to the choir Daniel
yeah which is one reason I don't spend a
whole lot of time on regenerative
consciousness and I loved seeing your
posts and all that but we all kind of
get it right who's ready to listen who
doesn't and so I'm spending my time
networking with business groups who are
interested you know so this is one group
out of Chicago called Nexus there's lots
of Nexus is this is an another Nexus
group founded by a brilliant physicist
who's actually and may change physics as
we know it and he's also a multi male
and he lives to network and he lives to
introduce and so he basically finds
people who are doing work around
sustainability who are kind and loving
mm-hmm that's his that's his criteria
kind loving and people are doing great
work in sustainability so through
whatever mechanism I've been invited to
become part of that group and it is an
amazing group of brilliant people
through that he he asked me to prepare
the next conference to actually run the
next conference with another guy named
Paul Stoltz who run who does something
called the adversity quotient and so
yeah I never heard of it but it's he
said basically he's a psychologist
neuroscientist organizational
development guy and this is now taught
at Harvard and MIT and around the world
we've got business he's
multi-millionaire instead of IQ which
doesn't really indicate much about
success IQs intelligent quotients is
kind of a bullshit indicator what he
found out is people who handle adversity
well are the people who are successful
so he's developed a battery of tests and
ways to improve your adversity quotient
which by the way is so I stopped them
and I said wait a minute let me just
explain this work that I'm hearing from
our perspective I talked about you know
internal locus of control and external
considering and internal locus an
external locus of control internal
considering and South Oregon is itself
observing and self remembering and he
said exactly that's the same stuff there
okay
I get it so I challenged him I said so
you're working on our individual and he
does business all over the world Daniel
because there are businesses out there
who and what I'm cut what I'm
captivating about is that there are
business that are businesses many many
many businesses we're saying yes we know
it is about our own development
that's gigantic if I can so I'm actually
so I flew out
to California to meet with them just two
weeks ago to see if there was some way
that we confuse into a kind of a whole
new platform what he's doing as an entry
point and our work and second and third
line work and whole systems work somehow
introduced this in a different way to
the world instead of hanging your hat on
regeneration we hang it on I don't know
something some new fusion but certainly
the level of adversity quotient and I
don't know come up with something new I
don't want to collapse it into just that
domain that dimension so anyway that's
something that I'm exploring hmm and the
other is is that with this found this
physicist that founded Nexus just
brought me an email yesterday and said
he feels that the resources that are
available in Nexus need to be focused on
regenerative work so I wrote back and I
said that's kind of an answer to a
prayer
let's see what we can this is certainly
something that is happening also in the
guy in October had an opportunity to we
got contacted by somebody and one of
them power of my time to just have a
Skype conversation and I've I'm sure
you've long been in that situations like
how that's another conversation how do
you how do you decide who to say yes to
I know it's a tough one I get that all
the time yeah and also when do you start
charging for your time because I
realized that I had a period where I was
spending 20 to 40 hours a month on those
kind of exploratory calls anything from
helping a guy get clearer on what he was
going to do his PhD on to somebody and
running the entire business idea past me
and and just wanting to pick my brains
on some suggestions of how they could do
it differently and and and very often I
get very friendly while this may have
been a very useful conversation and I
kind of go yeah it has
but more for you than for me and and and
ultimately I'm now stressed in getting
my paid work done because I choose but
anyway I'm getting sidetracked here well
no but Daniel I would love to share I
would love to share you because I've
wrestled with this for 40 years I would
love to share with that my perspective
with you let's come back to that
immediately I just want to finish that
story that I was building up towards and
in October I got contacted by somebody
who initially I was tempted to say no to
and then I had one of the most wonderful
conversations I've had all of last year
with him connecting in a really deep way
so very much on a personal note and long
story short I was invited to Switzerland
to a meeting that was about helping to
bring more funding into large ecosystems
restoration projects and I'm right that
are fundamentally community focused and
based that are all about drawing I
basically place sourced in in Regenesis
language and they brought 24 of us
together and half of the group or
slightly more than half of the group
were from the funding and philanthropy
and an impact investment world and this
is the smaller half were were people
like William Farina from common land or
Philippa vieja from renature so people
who had foundations that are doing that
kind of work out there and and it was
like the Omidyar Network like the eBay
people and and IKEA Foundation and very
big like the like alcohols investment
[Music]
system like like investment fund there
are just huge amounts of money wanting
to be poured into restoring damaged
ecosystems restoring or regenerating
damaged communities and really that the
money is there yeah
the issue that I again and this comes
back to
- how do we keep the depth of the work
and put the personal and the
consciousness and personal shift of re
relating of Riyadh yeah I think it I
Center just to give you a quick answer I
think it's a branding issue day and you
know and I think the I think the
principles are really powerful in that
regard I think we just have to keep
driving home principles and what and
then people will ask a question you know
people don't learn until they're willing
to ask a question and so our job is to
keep pushing stuff out there not to add
a gently gently destabilizing way which
is by the way but why we use the
language we use mm-hmm is to is so that
people are not assuming they understand
what you're saying is if they assume
they understand they don't need you if
they actually well what does that word
mean or you're using it in a slightly
different sense how come you said that
okay that's you don't and and you notice
that that I always have a story
associated with words I don't know if
you noticed that but I I try to do that
so that people actually can then image
that in a new way mm-hmm no you
shouldn't list let the words hang out
there and be a jerk about it that's
that's jargon you know that's jargon
abuse but but jargon is very important
because when it's precise it actually
has a unique meaning and that's that's
the mission so I think instead of just
talking about regeneration all the time
we actually have to start defining the
boundaries or the that's the wrong word
but the principles of regeneration in
that context so that people start going
diving deeper like in regenerative
consciousness that work could be great
to start using those principles and
having a deeper debate about that
because I know that many of the people
on that list sir are at that very
sensitive level about understanding the
need to be whole and certainly working
with nature on its own terms
what does that require of us and how do
we expand that then but I've noticed
that with my work in social media look
whether it's the regenerative and
cultures page or the regenerative
consciousness group and now we've even
started a regenerative Action Network
yeah I think I decided I was just
yesterday and is that it's a it was bit
disheartening for me to see some of the
comments because I realized how many
people that that were on the one hand
very interested in all all of this are
still really strongly in the habit of
other ring of just getting triggered by
one or two comments that make people
classify a person into a box and then
respond to that box and basically say
anybody who believes that is not one of
mine and so I'm against the most like it
is immediately polarizing there and and
and so for me these groups still have a
long way to go to open a real embracing
diversity valuing this force on on how
how we can live the questions together
would be my language yeah well love it
loving each other to evolve is it and I
mean that's why I still still put a
significant amount of time into these
these groups is then I do actually feel
that we're not necessarily talking to
the choir it's just like people who have
kind of begun to walk over a bridge but
but but then they haven't crossed it yet
yes well that's true but but the quad I
greet I agree with everything you just
said and there's something I want to add
to that and I'm trying to get my way
around it you know here another way to
say this is none of us are members of
the choir and that and that we we're all
developing right so maybe that's the way
to say it is that are we all on this
developmental art and do we are we all
friends and the work as the expression
do you have you heard that from our
practice mm-hmm
I happen to love that but are we friends
are we friends in the work yeah
that's a lovely expression they for me I
just remembered a another thing that I
wanted to ask you just um I I read with
a lot of what I learned in the
regenerative practitioner there were
moments where I felt that there there
was a similarity with some of the work
that I've drawn from through the
international futures forum particularly
Toni Hodgman and Bill sharp I'm sure
we've developed the three horizons
framework in the worlds systems model
and and there's a there they've now
curated a set at what they call
generative methodologies and in a way of
helping people to explore getting closer
to what regeneration would would mean
drawings heavily on on particularly
Pamela and Ben's book or the Regenesis
book em and they're fully aware that
there is this story that Regenesis holds
this this very long curated process and
lineage I would love to help to make
that bridge and I think bill bill would
really appreciate if when it's with you
or with the idea I'd be I would be glad
to do that in fact there was a guy in
Wellington New Zealand who gave me a
great article on the three horizons
which helped open that up to me I could
use some more of that I would love to do
that Daniel see if I send a separate
email but what I would love is like
basically if bill could spend 30 35
minutes presenting something to you Ben
and Pamela and then just get your
feedback as honest as it comes like they
know like because he would really
appreciate it and and I like he'd go yes
you can site you can sign me up for that
mind off panel will be game she's kind
of she said her world at Ben I think Ben
might be really game for it so then I
would be glad to do that I would
certainly be glad to do that because I
am interested in the three horizons and
would like would like a deeper
explanation is I I think that there is
this complementarity because I very
strongly remember permanence
to me after the therapy we really want
this work to be in constant development
because that's it the essence of it that
it needs it as you just said so
wonderfully and and then I felt it there
was a little like I haven't found my way
of how can I contribute to development
like maybe it's because I still need to
do a lot more assimilating and learning
of the world
no there well we're again we're all in
that we're all in that boat but I think
this is a longer conversation where I
and but but seriously Daniel a hundred
percent I am really interested in three
horizons thanks like I respect your
appreciation of bills work okay I said
I've spent some time with it but I would
like some hand-holding with it yeah
excellent set that up yeah super a no
and I'll let Ben know or you can let
both of us know and we'll invite Pam
what she wants one of the the things
that that for me was one of the absolute
highlights of last year and if you both
happened in the in the same event like
meeting um Jason 12 was was just
wonderful he's such an amazing guy and I
just felt really connected when I just
recently had a call with him just before
Christmas at that same meeting which was
in the Commonwealth meeting in London
and I believe you in did you men when
you went over to New Zealand to Auckland
to teach the TRP did you meet a lot of
Johnnie Freelander or think so
well I that whole like the magic that
you guys started to catalyze in the bay
of Auckland and and in New Zealand with
the highest density of regenerative
practitioners in the world and then this
wonderful blend between em our our our
Western verbalization of some deep life
principles and and patterns that of
course the Mary's been holding a cloud
for thousands of years another way of
wording same thing because it's its
essence its true its
really did I did I tell you the greatest
compliment I ever got no this is I love
this story so I facilitated the first
Maori and Pakeha the sustainability
planning group in Auckland and the
planning group anyway so there's much
longer story about this but in the
middle of the session this guy big Maori
guy comes up to me and jabs his finger
in my chest he says you believe what we
do how do you convince the white man and
I'm a pasty-faced white guy so I thought
that was a great compliment right and I
said I said listen I'm not here to teach
you anything I want to learn from you
and he said I said so where do you start
he said well we start with the universe
I said well that's exactly right and
how's it working for you he said well
it's not I said good maybe we do have
something to share mmm that was the
genesis of that work I like this guy
Johnny Freelander he's part of that
Network and he so as I understood from
our conversation has just recently
harshali's kind of inspired Mike did you
need to go somewhere yeah I just saw I
realized I'm we got a can we reschedule
can we keep going I've got a meeting
yeah I don't I don't actually okay can
you can you write something write that
down so what's another well actually
let's get some agenda items cuz I would
love to spend more time this is really
helpful for me Daniel helps me express
anyway if you're a game I'm gay
absolutely I'd love that I'll send you
an e-mail and we'll reschedule and okay
I'm sorry I'm I'm sorry I had to anyway
no busy day okay wonder thanks Daniel
love you bye bye